어지러운 전국 시대.
It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over
Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
Karakuri Martial Artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri Martial Artist!
무사시 등장이오!
Musashi is here-dasu!
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden
Musashi Road
(The Story of Karakuri Martial Artist: Road of Musashi)
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
A man always dreams of the day
제일 강해질 날을
in the center of the world to become
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
AH! AH! the strongest
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
모험의 길의 막을 연다
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
내일은 빛난다
Tomorrow will be glorious
격렬한 승부의 소리는
The sound of fierce duels
눈부신 인생
makes life dazzling
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Fight the utmost with the stillness
무예! 이도류 무사시
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
His eyes shined! Musashi!
홋카이도로 건너가던 도중, 무사시 일행의 배는 북쪽 바다를 어지럽히는 해적 오니고로시에게 공격받고 말았다.
During their trip to Hokkaido, Musashi and others were
attacked by Onigoroshi, the pirate that was rampaging on the northern sea.
아버지의 원수를 갚기 위해 카라쿠리 상어를 쫒던 다이스케하고 만난 센히메는 바다의 사내의 늠름함에 마음이 끌린다.
Senhime met with Daisuke, who was chasing Karakuri Shark in order to have
revenge for his father,and was moved by his valiantness.
다이스케를 도와 싸운 무사시와 코지로.
Musashi and Kojirō fought, helping Daisuke.
세찬 사투 끝에, 싸움은 이겼지만, 센히메의 마음은 찌부러지고 말았다.
After an intense fight, they won the fight, but Senhime's heart was crushed.
홋카이웨스턴의 사투이오
Desperate Struggle
in Hokkai-Western
그건 그렇고...
By the way...
이 자들은 공복이었다.
They were hungry.
춥다 했더니 눈이라니...
Snow, right when I was feeling cold...
엎친 데 덮친 격이군요.
Misfortunes never come singly, eh...
배, 배가 고프오.
I- I'm hungry-dasu.
오늘로 4일째이오. 아무거나 좋으니까 먹고 싶소.
It's already fourth day today-dasu. I want to eat anything, no matter what it is-dasu.
시끄럽다! 큰 소리 내지 마라! 배에 울리긴...
Shut up! Keep quiet! It's ringing in our stomachs...
그렇게 배고픈 건 무사시뿐만이 아냐.
You aren't the only one hungry here, Musashi.
그것도 따져보면 네 탓이잖아?
Moreover, it's all your fault, to be specific.
그런 소릴 해도, 배가 고파서 뱃가죽이 등짝에 붙었소.
Say whatever you want, but my stomach is on my back because I'm too hungry-dasu.
이런 곳에서 셋이 모여 길에 쓰러져 죽고 마는가...
So, we three are going to die on a road at nowhere at a place like this...
젠장... 이것도 죄다 지갑을 무사시한테 맡긴 게 틀렸던 거야!
Damn... I knew it was a bad idea to entrust the wallet to Musashi!
뭔 소리이오! 여관에서 누가 지갑을 훔쳐간 건 내 탓만이 아니오!
Who are you blaming at-dasu?! It's not only my fault that someone stole the wallet-dasu!
도둑! 도둑! 해도 아무도 쫒으러 나오지 않았잖소!
Thief! Thief! I yelled, but nobody came out to chase-dasu!
대체 센짱, 뭘 하고 있었소!
Most of all, Sen-chan, what were you doing-dasu?!
어? 나, 나는 목욕하고 있었지.
Oh? Uh, well, I was taking a bath.
아침에 두 시간이라니 문제가 있소.
You have problems, if you really have to spend 2 hours for that in mornings.
헤, 어라? 그렇게나 들어가 있었어?
Oh, is that true? Did I take that much time?
코지로! 너 뭐하고 있었소!
Kojirō! What were you doing-dasu?!
나, 나는 출발 전의 준비를...
I- I was preparing for another trip...
딱 완벽해 보이는구나!
I look perfect, great!
뭐야! 뭔 불만이라도 있냐!
What?! Do you have anything to say?!
흥! 보아하니 머리 만지고 있었겠소!
Hmph! I know you were just fiddling with your hair-dasu!
차림새에 신경쓰는 것도 무사의 소양. 특히 내 정도로 괜찮은 사내가 되려면 말야.
Caring about personal appearance is also a swordsman's manner, especially when you want to be a nice man, like me.
어딜 봐서?
A nice man like you, eh?
뭐?!
What?!
칼 빼라, 무사시!
Take it out, Musashi!
때려쳐! 창피해! 누가 보면 아주 꼴사납겠다!
Forget it! You're embarrassing me! If someone ever looks at this, it would be so shameful!
덤벼드시오!
Face me!
센히메 님! 염려할 필요 없사옵니다! 애초에 이런 수준 떨어지는 남자하고 여행을 하고 있던 게 틀렸던 것이옵니다!
Senhime! Don't worry about this! It was a bad idea at the first place to have a journey with a low-class man like that guy!
무사시! 사과할 마지막 기회다!
Musashi! It's your last chance to apologize!
흥! 내가 보기엔 그 쪽이 잘난 척 잔뜩 하던 게 눈엣가시던 참이오!
Hmph! Your conceited attitude was really becoming a pain in the ass-dasu!
역으로 쓰러뜨려 주겠소!
You're going down instead-dasu!
죽어라, 무사시!
Die, Musashi!
잠깐.
One moment.
음식 냄새이오!
I smell food-dasu!
이건 삿포로 라면의 냄새이오!
This is the smell of Sapporo ramen-dasu!
정말이냐, 무사시!
Are you sure about that, Musashi?!
내 코는 거짓말 안 하오!
My nose does not lie-dasu!
마을이야!
A village!
음식이오!
Food-dasu!
살았다!
We're saved!
만세! 만세! 만세!
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
자, 맛있는 라면이요! 몸이 따뜻해져요!
Here, here! Tasty ramen for you! It'll make your body warm!
손님, 돼지고기는 서비스요!
Pork fillet is free, dear customers!
돼지고기! 말린 죽순! 알 넣어서 곱배기로 된장라면 지금 당장!
Pork fillet! Dried bamboo shoots! Put eggs in, in double size, and give me a soybean paste ramen immediately!
그걸 초곱배기로!
In quadruple size!
나, 게다가 그걸 셋 주시오!
And on top of that, give me three of those-dasu!
우리가 운영하는 가게에 오다니, 너희들도 참 운이 좋아!
You guys are lucky, to find my store first!
정말 덕분에 살았소!
You really saved us-dasu!
이 은혜는 꼭 갚을게요.
We will never forget your kindness to us.
아니, 이 세상에선 구해주고 구함받고, 기브 앤 테이크지!
Nah, we just rescue and be rescued! Give and take, that is!
우리도 홋카이도에 신천지를 찾으러 왔어.
We came to Hokkaido to find a new world.
그래도 이렇게 재회할 줄이야!
Still, I never expected to meet you here!
정말 세상은 넓고도 좁소!
The world is wide, but narrow at once-dasu!
바이켄 씨가 만든 라면, 맛있었어!
Your ramen was really great, Mr. Baiken!
음, 나도 라면을 자주 먹었지만, 그렇게 맛있는 건 처음이었다!
Agreed. I eat ramen often, but that was the best one I've ever had!
고마우이, 고미워! 땡큐다! 그래도, 난 라면 만들려고 홋카이도에 온 게 아냐!
Thank you, thank you! But you know, I'm not here at Hokkaido to make ramens!
알고 있소! 분명 그 쿠사리가마로 출세하려고!
We know that-dasu! You're trying to success in life with that Kusarigama!
말할 필요도 없지! 이 녀석들도 쭉 고생해 왔으니.
No need to explain more! Also these little guys have gone through troubles, too.
귀엽네!
How cute!
-뭣이오?
-그러게...
-What was that?
-I wonder...
오빠, 무서워!
Brother, I'm scared!
괜찮아! 저건 철포 소리야.
It's alirght! That's a sound of gun.
음, 화승총이다.
Yeah, must be a matchlock.
마, 마차 소리이오?
I- is it sound of a covered wagon-dasu?
마, 마타조!
M- Matazo!
왜 그래, 마타조!
What's wrong, Matazo?!
당했어?!
Did you get hit?!
고즈케, 앞으로는 네게 맡긴다!
Gozuke, it's now all up to you!
젠장!
Damn!
제기랄! 제기랄! 제기랄!
Dammit! Dammit! Dammit!
쓰러졌다!
He's taken down!
죽은 거야?
Is he dead?
아니, 그래도 이대로는 안 되겠어.
No, but he doesn't look good at this rate.
네놈들은 누구냐!
Who are you guys?!
아무것도 묻지 말고 여기서 물러나라!
Do not ask anything, and get away from here!
-닌자구나.
-닌자?
-They're ninjas.
-Ninja?
포, 포장마차를... 저, 저걸 빼앗기면 동료 개척민이 몰살당하고...
T- the covered wagon... I- if they take it from us, fellow settlers will be annihilated...
개척민이 몰살?
Settlers will be annihilated?
어떻게 되어가는 거야?
What's going on here?
우, 우리는...
W- we are...
아직 이야기는 안 끝났소!
The conversation is not over yet-dasu!
멋져!
Cool!
이야, 드문 기회를 잡았소!
I took a rare chance-dasu!
센히메 님, 얘들 잠깐 맡아 주세요.
Senhime, please take care of the kids for a moment.
네!
Got it!
뭐가 문제냐? 그게 다냐?
What's the problem? Is that all you can do?
어디서든 달려들어 보시오!
Come attack wherever you are-dasu!
싸구려 칼 쓰고 있소...
You must be using a cheap sword-dasu...
퇴, 퇴각! 퇴각!
R- retreat! Retreat!
이시카리 강을 따라서 홋카이 고원을 개척해서 겨우 작물을 얻을 수 있게 된 건데...
Following Ishikari River, we've cultivated Hokkai Highlands and finally managed to harvest crops...
거, 거기에 놈들이 공격해 와서...
T- they came to attack...
말도 안 되는 소리를 지껄이고...
Asked us for something unreasonable...
우린 요새를 새워서 싸웠지만...
We've built a fortress and fought...
별 건 아니었어.
It wasn't something great.
버티긴 했어.
We've stood somehow.
그리고 있는 대로 무기를 모아...
And we've gathered available weapons...
나하고 마타조 둘이서 요새에서 빠져나와 삿포로 거리에서 대포하고 탄약을 손에 넣었지만...
We two, Matazo and I, sneaked out from the fortress and got cannons and ammo from the streets of Sapporo,
녀석들이 냄새를 맡고...
they found it out...
그렇게 된 것이었소!
So that's what happened-dasu!
나쁜 놈들이네, 그 닌자들!
Those ninjas are bad guys!
사람이 땀 흘려가며 열심히 얻은 걸 가로채다니 용서할 수 없어!
It's unforgivable to take things that people worked so hard to obtain!
부탁해... 저 포장마차를 홋카이 요새에... 요새에...
Please... Take that covered wagon to Hokkai Fortress... to the fortress...
어디 있소, 그 홋카이 요새는!
Where is that Hokkai Fortress?!
홋카이 고원에 있으?
Is it at Hokkai Highlands?
-그, 그래.
-그, 그럼 내가 알아!
-Y- yes.
-T- then, I know well!
네 이름은!
What's your name?!
고, 고즈케...
G- Gozuke...
고즈케 씨랬지. 포장마차를 꼭 홋카이 요새에 보내 주겠어.
So you're Gozuke. We will send that covered wagon to Hokkai Fortress, no matter what.
그래! 가자!
Yeah! Let's go!
-좋다!
-여기서 안 가면 사내가 아니오!
-Agreed!
-It is not manly to go now-dasu!
당장 출발하오!
We're going right now!
고즈케의 묘
마타조의 묘
RIP Gozuke
RIP Matazo
겐운사이
Gen'unsai
녀석들, 안 따라오오...
They aren't chasing-dasu...
포기한 걸까.
I wonder if they gave up.
그건 순진합니다. 결국 저희 목적지는 놈들이 알고 있을 테니 매복하고 있을 수도 있습니다.
That is naive. They must be knowing our destination, so they should be lying in ambush.
매복?
Ambush?
언니, 바이켄 오빠가 있으니까 괜찮아!
Sis, it's alright, since Baiken is with us!
네, 네, 그래요!
Yeah, yeah, that's true!
이천일류! 십자 가르기!
Nitenichiryu, Ten(十) Shaped Cut!
만세!
Hooray!
어지러워!
I'm getting dizzy!
어떻게 될 것인가, 요 녀석들! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
What will happen to them?! Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
위험하오!
That's bad!
다들! 꽉 잡으라!
Everyone! Hold on tight!
해냈소!
You did it!
위기일발이었군!
It was so close!
그치? 바이켄 오빠가 있으면 괜찮댔지?
I told so! It's alright with Baiken!
정말, 바이켄 다시 봤네!
Yeah, I looked Baiken again!
젠장...
Damn...
가라.
Go.
요새가 보인다!
I can see the fortress!
저것이오?
Is that it?!
저게 요새야? 무사히 잘 있는 것 같네.
Is that the fortress? Looks safe for now.
그럼 좋겠습니다만...
I hope so...
누가 불을 피웠구나!
Someone set a fire!
소중한 밭을! 이 무슨 몹쓸 짓이냐!
How can they do that to these precious fields?!
둘러싸였소!
We're surrounded-dasu!
이 마차에 화약이 있지? 불이 붙으면
There's gunpowder in this wagon, right? If fire gets on this...
쾅!
BOOM!
놀라지 마, 이런 걸로!
Don't be scared by this!
니가 할 소리 아냐!
You're in no position to say that1
아, 그런가?
Oh, is that so?
바이켄 오빠가 있으니 괜찮다고 했지?
You said it's alright since Baiken is here!
내가 불을 후려 베어 넘겨서 길을 만들겠소!
I'll mow down the enemy and make a road!
아, 잠깐 기다려라! 뭐가 어쨌든 상대는 불이야!
Hey, just a moment! Our opponent is fire, no matter what you think!
멈춰라, 무사시! 나도 간다!
Stop, Musashi! I'll join!
나 혼자서 충분하오!
I myself is enough-dasu!
그러니까 잠깐 말야. 내게 생각이 있어.
Yeah, right. Just stop for now. I have an idea.
어, 어이, 봐라!
H- hey, look!
부, 불이다!
F- fire!
할아버님! 불이! 밭에 불이!
Grandfather! Fire! A fire is on the fields!
녀석들이 불을 붙였다!
They set a fire on the fields!
그런데 왜 밭에 불을...
But why would they set a fire on there...
연기만 내서 우리를 끌어내려는 거 아냐?
Aren't they trying to lure us out with smoke?
그럴 리가. 저게 연극일 리가 없잖아?
Probably not. You think that's an illusion?
저런, 이거 참 괜찮은 모닥불이네.
My, my. Isn't this a pretty good bonfire?
그럼 센히메 일행도 전소하는 거냐?
Well, wouldn't this burn down Senhime and others, too?
좋아! 무사시! 불은 일단 됐다!
It worked, Musashi! The fire is gone for now!
잠깐, 이거 하나 더 때려박소!
Wait, let me throw in this, one more-dasu!
필요 없어!
Not needed!
하하, 그렇소. 아깝소.
Haha, you're right-dasu. It's too worthy for that-dasu.
마차에 두고 오오!
I'll go put this on the wagon-dasu!
먼저 간다!
I'll go first, then!
기다리시오!
Wait for me-dasu!
그래도 말야, 역시 코지로 님! 화약의 폭풍으로 불을 끌 생각을 하다니 대단해!
Anyway, Kojirō really is bright, for thinking to put off the fire with the detonation blast of gunpowder!
칼이라면 지지 않소!
I do not lose in a sword fight-dasu!
무사시! 가자!
Musashi! Let's go!
좋소!
Right!
서둘러라, 무사시!
Hurry, Musashi!
같이 가오!
Wait for me-dasu!
쏴라, 쏴!
Open fire!
이렇게 된 바 총공격이 있을 뿐!
This leaves us only one choice - an all-out attack!
전원 출격!
Everyone, engage in battle!
온다!
Incoming!
총공격이다!
It's an all-out attack!
포장마차다! 고스케 일행이 돌아왔다!
A covered wagon! Gosuke's back!
좋아! 문을 열어라!
Great! Open the door!
고스케하고 마타조가 아니네!
They're not Gosuke and Matazo!
그 둘은 죽었슈!
Those two are dead!
어서! 총하고 대포를!
Hurry! Grab the guns and cannons!
모두! 빨리 이 총을!
Everyone! Hurry and take these guns!
고맙다!
Thanks!
팍팍 반격하시오!
Steadily counterattack-dasu!
쏴라!
Fire!
아끼지 말고 쏴라, 쏴!
Don't hesitate! Fire! Fire!
네놈들! 화전 맛 좀 봐라!
You bastards! Take some fiery darts!
어디 해 보자!
We'll do this soon!
음, 좋다!
Now!
불이다!
Fire!
불이다! 서둘러! 물 가지고 와! 어서!
Fire! Hurry! Go get some water! Now!
이제 틀렸다! 다 물러나라!
It's not good at this rate! Everyone, withdraw!
왔소!
They're here-dasu!
고집을 보여 주겠소!
We'll show our stubbornness-dasu!
이놈!
You brat!
넌 누구이오!
Who are you-dasu?!
난 홋카이 닌자 무리의 우두머리, 겐운사이.
I am Gen'unsai, the boss of Hokkai Ninja Group.
왜 개척민이 연 마을을 노리는 것이오!
Why are you aiming for a village that settles made-dasu?!
그런 것 따위는 네가 알 필요 없다!
You do not have to know that!
왜이오!
Why is that-dasu?!
흥, 넌 어차피 죽을 테니까다, 무사시!
Hmph! Because you're bound to die soon, Musashi!
왜 내 이름을 알고 있소! 홋카이도에서도 나 유명하오?
Why do you know my name-dasu?! Am I that famous even in Hokkaido-dasu?
뭣이오, 이렇게나 가득... 비겁하오!
What's this-dasu?! There are lots of you... that's cowardly-dasu!
문답무용!
No questions asked!
젠장!
Damn!
대체 누굴 상대해야 하오!
Who should I face?!
제, 젠장...
D- damn...
이 그림자는... 그렇소! 그림자를 보고 싸우면 되오!
That shadow... That's it! I can fight, looking at shadow!
네이놈!
You bastard!
이천일류 섬광검!
Nitenichiryu: Flash Sword!
건방지다!
How impudent!
투! 파이어!
Two! Fire!
바이켄, 정말 여기 남으오?
Baiken, are you really staying here-dasu?
밭을 보면 도무지 어떻게 할 수도 없고, 잇켄하고 얘들도 좋아하니까.
It can't be helped whenever there are fields in front of me. Moreover, Ikken and kids like it here, too.
그렇소! 그게 좋겠소.
I see-dasu! That'll be great-dasu.
먼 길을 거쳐 온 홋카이도도 무사시 일행을 얌전히 맞아 주지는 않았다.
Even when Musashi and others went a long way to reach Hokkaido, it didn't welcome them so nicely.
그렇지만 바이켄과의 우정도 깊어지고, 무사시의 마음은 홋카이도의 하늘처럼 맑았다.
But still, the friendship with Baiken got deeper, and Musashi's heart was as clean as the blue sky of Hokkaido.
허공의 주머니에 달이
Sometimes the moon jumps over
뛰어넘어가는 일도 있어
the pocket of empty sky
큰 소리로 웃으면
Laugh loudly and
내일에는 아침이 와
morning will come tomorrow
잃는 것 따위는 아무것도 아니야
Don't worry too much about losing
계속 해나가! 앞으로 가!
Keep going! Go for it!
맨손은 강해
A bare hand is strong
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
인생 그런 거야! 기회가 어라,
That's how life is! Look, a chance
꼬리를 흔들며 쫒아와!
follows us wagging its tail!
그런 거야! 가볍게 가자
That's how it is! Let's go lightly
미래도 그런 거야! 내일이 어라,
That's how the future is, too! Look, tomorrow
양손을 벌리고 웃고 있어!
is opening its hands and smiling at us!
이하 사천왕을 조종하는, 센짱을 없애 버리려고 하는 장본인은 어라, 한조였소!
The one who controlled Four Iga Kings, and the one who keeps trying to get rid of Senhime was - no way! - Hanzo-dasu!
오니히메, 지라이얀과 싸우는 우리. 그렇지만 홋카이도의 대설 속에선 우리가 불리하오!
We're fighting against Onihime and Jiraiyan, but we're at disadvantage, in a heavy snow of Hokkaido-dasu!
센짱을 데려가버려서 대위기!
They took Senhime, and we're in crisis-dasu!
다음 이야기! 쿠콰쾅! 카라쿠리 성채이오
Next story! Kaboom! Karakuri Stronghold
질풍노도의 큰 눈보라이오!
A stormy big snowstorm is waiting for us-dasu!
다음 이야기
쿠콰쾅!
카라쿠리 성채이오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
Kaboom!
Karakuri Stronghold
Look forwards for it!